Guide to the Thomas W. Streeter Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Files for Bibliography of Texas, 1921-61; Series I; 6; (15 boxes)
  - PART I: TEXAS IMPRINTS
    - Newspaper Research
      - Newspapers known only by Indirect Reference
        - Galveston, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 139-40)
        - Houston, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 141)
        - Huntsville, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 142)
        - Marshall, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 143)
        - Matagorda, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 144)
        - Matamoros, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 145)
        - Montgomery, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 146)
        - Nacogdoches, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 147)
        - San Antonia de Bexar, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 148)
        - San Felipe, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 149)
        - San Luis, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 150)
        - Washington, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 151)
        - Unknown place of publication, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 152)
      - Location Research
        - General notes, 1939, 1947, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 153-54)
        - Correspondence with Malcolm McLean, 1942-54 (Box 6, Folder 155)
          Related Archival Materials note
          See also: Box 67, folder 583-89
        - Correspondence with institutions, 1948-55 (Box 6, Folder 156-58)
          See also: Box 67, folder 572
        - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - PART II: MEXICAN IMPRINTS
    - Subject Files
      - Additions to Part II (Part III Appendix): references from the Latin Americana Collection, University of Texas, 1957, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 160)
      - Authors: biographical data, 1933-56, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 161-62)
      - Benson, Miss: thesis on the eastern internal provinces and Texas (Box 7, Folder 163)
      - Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state): constitution of 1826, 1955, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 164)
      - Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state): decrees, preliminary lists, 1939-55 (Box 7, Folder 165-68)
      - Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state): decrees, 1821-35, 1941-43 (Box 7, Folder 169)
      - Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state): decrees, 1834 (Box 7, Folder 170)
      - Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state): decrees omitted from Part II, 1941, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 171)
      - Coahuila and Texas(Mexican state): Gazeta del Gobierno (Box 7, Folder 172)
      - Diario del Gobierno de la Republica Mexicana 1836-45: items from, 1950-51 (Box 7, Folder 173-74)
      - Early notes and checklists: from Carlos Castañeda, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 175)
      - Laws: bibliographic data and locations for Arrilaga, Recopilacion de Leyes ... de la Republica Mexicana, and Dublan, Legislacion Mexicana ó coleccion completa de las Disposiciones, 1955, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 176-77)
      - Laws for the Better Admininstration of Justice in Texas, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 178)
      - Memorias, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 179)
      - Mina expedition of 1817, 1947-48, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 180-82)
      - Newspapers, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 183)
      - Tamaulipas (Mexican state): laws, 1827, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 184)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1952-56, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - PART III: UNITED STATES AND EUROPEAN IMPRINTS
    - Subject Files
      - Annexation speeches: United States congressional speeches on Texas, 1958 (Box 7a, Folder 186-87)
      - Arkansas Gazette, 1939-53 (Box 7a, Folder 187.1)
      - Authors biographical data, DATE (Box 7a, Folder 188)
        See also: Bibliographic checking
      - Bayer, Herbert O.
        See: Box 9, folder 232
      - Beales, John Charles: publications, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 189)
      - Bibliographic checking: information from Marie E. Becker, 1958-60 (Box 7a, Folder 189.1-.7)
      - Brown, John Henry, The Fall of the Alamo, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 190)
      - Castro, Henri, 1940, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 191)
      - Castro, Henri, Memorial, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 192)
      - Champ d'Asile: lithographs, 1940-61 (Box 7a, Folder 193)
        See also: Box 68, folder 602
      - Champ d'Asile: notes, 1937, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 194)
      - Channing, William Henry: letter to Henry Clay, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 195)
      - Chivers, Thomas Hulley, Nacoochee, 1929, 1933 (Box 7a, Folder 196)
      - Clay, Cassius: annexation speeches, 1940, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 197)
      - Coahuila and Texas: publication of colonization laws in the United States, 1945 (Box 7a, Folder 198)
      - Crockett Almanacs, 1950, 1952, n.d. (Box 7a, Folder 199)
      - Dolbeare, Benjamin, Narrative, 1940-58 (Box 7a, Folder 200)
      - Dominquez Grant, 1956 (Box 7a, Folder 201)
      - Edwards, Munroe: biographical sketch by Louis W. Kemp, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 202)
      - Edwards, Munroe: trial, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 203)
      - Ehrenberg, Hermann: diary, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 204)
      - Field, Joseph, Three Years in Texas, 1937-53, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 205-06)
      - Foote, Henry S., Texas and Texans (Box 8, Folder 207)
      - Franz, George, Die Auswanderung, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 208)
      - Galveston: Jean Laffite's settlement proposals, 1938, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 209)
      - German books in Part III: synopses, 1958, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 210-12)
      - German books relating to Texas, 1929-30 (Box 8, Folder 213)
      - Giraud, Jacob: A Description...North American Birds, 1956, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 214)
      - Gregg, Josiah, Commerce of the Prairies, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 215)
      - Hofland, Barbara, Stolen Boy, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 216)
      - Holley, Mary (Austin): 1830s letters, 1953-54 (Box 8, Folder 216.1)
      - Houston, Matilda, Texas and the Gulf of Mexico, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 217)
      - Houston (city) plan, 1957, 1960, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 218)
      - Humboldt, Alexander, Carte Générale, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 219)
      - Keene, Richard Raynal: publications, 1941, 1957, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 220)
      - Kendall, George Wilkins, Narrative of the Texan Santa Fé Expedition, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 221)
      - Leftwich Grant, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 222)
      - Manouvrier Map, 1839, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 223)
      - Maps of Texas
      - Maps of Texas, 1795-1845, 1928-37 (Box 8, Folder 224-25)
      - Maps of Texas, 1830-1868, 1937-58 n.d. (Box 8, Folder 226-27)
      - Maps of Texas, 1830-1868, 1937-58 n.d. (Box 9, Folder 228)
      - Mercer, Charles F.: Mercer colony case, 1941-58, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 229-30)
      - Niles, John Milton, and Pease, Lorraine Thompson, History of South America and Mexico (Box 9, Folder 231)
      - Nolan, Philip: correspondence with Herbert O. Bayer, 1945-46 (Box 9, Folder 232)
      - Pagès, Pierre M. F. viconte de, Travels Around the World, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 233)
      - Parker, James and Plummer, Rachel: captive narratives, 1927-56 (Box 9, Folder 234)
      - Picornel, Juan M., 1944 (Box 9, Folder 235)
      - Racknitz, Baron Johann von, 1957, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 236)
      - Robinson, J. H., 1938 (Box 9, Folder 236.1)
      - Ross, Reuben: land grant (Box 9, Folder 237)
      - Sedgwick, Theodore, Thoughts on the Proposed Annexation, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 238)
      - Snell, P. lithographer, 1942, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 239)
      - Snider-Pellegrini, A., 1950-51 (Box 9, Folder 240)
      - Snively expedition, 1945, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 241)
      - Texas Provisional Government Commissioners, 1835-1836, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 242)
      - Texian Grand March 1835, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 243)
      - United States Congress. Joint Resolution of Annexation, December 1845, 1950, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 244)
      - United States Presidents: messages regarding Texas, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 245)
      - Wharton, William H., Address, 1836, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 246)
      - White, Joseph M., Speech, 1838, 1957-58 (Box 9, Folder 247)
    - Location Research--Institutions
      - American Antiquarian Society, 1958-59 (Box 9, Folder 248)
      - American Geographical Society, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 249-50)
      - Bancroft Library, 1958-19 (Box 9, Folder 251-52)
      - Baylor University Library, 1958-59 (Box 9, Folder 253-55)
      - Boston Athenaeum, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 256-57)
      - Boston Public Library, 1958-59 (Box 9, Folder 258-60)
      - Dallas Public Library, 1958-59 (Box 10, Folder 261-62)
      - Fort Worth Public Library, 1958-59 (Box 10, Folder 263-65)
      - Harvard University Libraries, 1958-59 (Box 10, Folder 266-69)
      - Henry E. Huntington Library, 1958-59 (Box 10, Folder 270)
      - Houston Public Library, 1958-59 (Box 10, Folder 271-73)
      - Library Company of Philadelphia, 1957, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 274)
      - Library of Congress, 1958-60 (Box 10, Folder 275-81)
      - Massachusetts Historical Society, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 282)
      - New-York Historical Society, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 283-84)
      - New York Public Library, 1958-60 (Box 11, Folder 285-89)
      - Newberry Library, 1957-58 (Box 11, Folder 290-91)
      - Presbyterian Historical Society, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 292)
      - Princeton University Library, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 292.1)
      - Rosenberg Library, 1958-59 (Box 11, Folder 293-95)
      - San Antonio Public Library, 1958-59 (Box 11, Folder 296-97)
      - Southern Methodist University Library, 1959, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 298-99)
      - Texas State Library, 1958-59 (Box 11, Folder 300-01)
      - University of California Library, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 302)
      - University of Illinois Library, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 303)
      - University of Texas Library, 1958-59, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 304-09)
      - William L. Clements Library, 1958-59 (Box 12, Folder 310-11)
      - Yale University Libraries, 1958-60 (Box 12, Folder 312-13)
        See also: Dallas Public Library finding lists, Box 10, folder 262
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1958, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 314)
    - Location Research--Private Collections
      - Everett D. Graff Collection, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 315)
      - Paul Ragsdale Collection, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 316)
- Preliminary Entries and Drafts, 1922-58; Series II; 17.25; (49 boxes)
  Series II, housed in Boxes 13-61, contains notes and drafts divided into the three Parts of the Bibliography of Texas 1795-1845.
  - PART I: TEXAS IMPRINTS
    - Notes on Public Printing: records at the Texas State Library (reported by McLean), 1954 (Box 13, Folder 317)
    - Winkler's Notes on Texas material at Yale University (Parts I and III), 1929-30 (Box 13, Folder 318)
    - Broadsides: early drafts, 1945-45, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 319)
    - Exclusions, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 320)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1813-1845, 1939-51, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 321-22)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1813-1845, 1939-51, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 323-24)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1813-1845, 19139-51, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 325-26)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1813-1845, 1939-51, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 327-28)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1813-1845, 1939-51, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 329)
    - Notes taken from Original Entries of Printer's Copy, 1837-1845, 1945-50, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 330)
    - Notes taken from Original Entries of Printer's Copy, 1837-1845, 1945-50, n.d. (Box 20, Folder 331-32)
    - Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 333-34)
    - Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 335-36)
    - Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 337-38)
    - Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 339-40)
    - Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 341-42)
    - Notes from Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 343-44)
    - Notes from Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 345-46)
    - Notes from Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 347-48)
    - Notes from Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 349-50)
    - Notes from Final Draft for Printer, 1813-1845, 1939-47, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 351-52)
  - PART II: MEXICAN IMPRINTS
    - Preliminary Checklist of Imprints of the Four Internal Provinces of Eastern Mexico (Texas, Tamaulipas, Nuevo Leon, and Coahuila), 1817-1824 (Box 31, Folder 353)
    - Preliminary Checklist of Imprints of the Free State of Coahuila and Texas (exclusive of newspapers and those decrees reprinted by Kimball), 1824-1835 (Box 31, Folder 354)
    - Wagner's Notes on Part II: broadsides at Yale University (annotated by Winkler and Greene), 1929-39, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 355)
    - Coahuila and Texas items in Yale broadsides, 1940-55 (Box 32, Folder 356)
    - Coahuila and Texas items in Yale broadsides: Carbons, 1940-55 (Box 33, Folder 357)
    - Mexican Broadsides not Coahuila and Texas, 1939-55 (Box 33, Folder 358)
    - Mexican Imprints outside of Coahuila and Texas, 1803-1846, 1926-46 (Box 34, Folder 359-60)
    - Mexican Imprints outside of Coahuila and Texas, 1803-1846: Carbons, 1927-60 (Box 35, Folder 361-62)
    - Entries Omitted Since February 1952, 1952, n.d. (Box 36, Folder 363-64)
    - Entries Omitted Since February 1952, 1952, n.d. (Box 37, Folder 365)
    - Miscellaneous Entries, 1939-55 (Box 37, Folder 366)
    - Miscellaneous Entries, 1939-55 (Box 38, Folder 367)
    - Original Entries Returned from Printers, 1795-1845, 1939-56, n.d. (Box 38, Folder 368)
    - Original Entries Returned from Printers, 1795-1845, 1939-56, n.d. (Box 39, Folder 369)
    - Carbons with Location Reports for Texas institutions by McLean, 1946-56, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 370)
    - Carbons with Location Reports for Texas institutions by McLean, 1946-56, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 371)
  - PART III: UNITED STATES AND EUROPEAN IMPRINTS
    See also: Box 13, folder 318
    - Broadside: early drafts, 1938-47, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 372)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Maps and other Entries, 1958, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 373)
    - Exclusions, 1946-59, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 374)
    - Location Reports for Texas Institutions by McLean, 1950-53 (Box 43, Folder 375-77)
    - Location Reports for Texas Institutions by Mclean, 1950-53 (Box 44, Folder 378)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1799-1845, 1939-47 (Box 44, Folder 379-80)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1799-1845, 1939-47 (Box 45, Folder 381-82)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1799-1845, 1939-47 (Box 46, Folder 383-85)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1799-1845, 1939-47 (Box 47, Folder 386-88)
    - Preliminary Entries, 1799-1845, 1939-47 (Box 48, Folder 389-90)
    - Printer's Copy, 1799-1845, 1940-57 (Box 48, Folder 391)
    - Printer's Copy, 1799-1845, 1940-57 (Box 49, Folder 392-94)
    - Printer's Copy, 1799-1845, 1940-57 (Box 50, Folder 395-97)
    - Printer's Copy, 1799-1845, 1940-57 (Box 51, Folder 398-99)
    - Notes from Printer's Copies, 1796-1845, 1941-50 (Box 51, Folder 400-01)
    - Notes from Printer's Copies, 1796-1845, 1941-50 (Box 52, Folder 402)
    - Notes, Originals, 1795-1845, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 403)
    - Notes, Originals, 1795-1845, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 404)
    - Carbons of Entries, 1795-1845, 1922-58 (Box 54, Folder 405)
    - Carbons of Entries, 1795-1845, 1922-58 (Box 55, Folder 406)
    - Carbons of Entries, 1795-1845, 1922-58 (Box 56, Folder 407)
    - Carbons of Entries, 1795-1845, 1922-58 (Box 57, Folder 408)
    - Carbons of Entries, 1795-1845, 1922-58 (Box 58, Folder 409-10)
    - Carbons of Notes, 1795-1845, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 411)
    - Carbons of Notes, 1795-1845, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 412)
    - Cross-References, 1946-58 (Box 61, Folder 413-14)
- Photoreproductions, 1927-80; Series III; 2; (5 boxes)
  Series III, housed in Boxes 62-66, is divided into photoreproductions of items included in the Bibliography of Texas 1795-1845 and those omitted. The first section is arranged according to the numbers used in the bibliography and the second by date of publication.
  - INCLUDED IN BIBLIOGRAPHY OF TEXAS
    Folders with fuller titles usually indicate photoreproductions of an entire work, not just the title page.
    - No. 5. Mexico (republic). Supremo Poder Ejecutivo, 1946 (Box 62, Folder 415)
    - No. 7. Texas (province). Junta Gubernativa, 1946 (Box 62, Folder 416)
    - No. 9. Austin, Stephen Fuller [Form of certificate], 1940-48 (Box 62, Folder 417)
    - No. 10. Austin, Stephen Fuller [Form of promissory note], 1940-45 (Box 62, Folder 418)
    - No. 13 (note). Austin, Stephen Fuller [Form of deed], 1947-48 (Box 62, Folder 419)
    - No. 15. Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state). Comisionado General, 1942 (Box 62, Folder 420)
    - No. 24. Austin, John. To the Public, 1941 (Box 62, Folder 421)
    - No. 28 (note). Cotten, Godwin Brown [Article in Constitutional Advocate], 1947, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 422)
    - No. 32. Texas. Constitution, October, 1832, 1935-45 (Box 62, Folder 423)
    - No. 78-89, 1932, 1945, n.d. (Box 62, Folder 424)
    - No. 91. Texas (provisional government). Consultations, November, 1835, 1927-45 (Box 62, Folder 425)
    - No. 92-146, 1939-45 (Box 62, Folder 426)
    - No. 154-172, 1928-48 (Box 62, Folder 427)
    - No. 181-195, 1928-49 (Box 62, Folder 428)
    - No. 197-249, 1927-46 (Box 62, Folder 429)
    - No. 250-277, 1927-46 (Box 62, Folder 430)
    - No. 278-299, 1927-46 (Box 62, Folder 431)
    - No. 301-327, 1927-46 (Box 62, Folder 432)
    - No. 329. Sabine. Company of the City of Sabine...Certificate of Stock, 1932-53 (Box 62, Folder 433)
    - No. 334-336, 1932-46 (Box 62, Folder 434)
    - No. 338. Texas (provisional government). Laws. Index to Ordinances, 1927-48 (Box 62, Folder 435)
    - No. 339-359, 1927-46 (Box 62, Folder 436)
    - No. 360-379, 1927-48 (Box 62, Folder 437)
    - No. 381-400, 1927-53 (Box 62, Folder 438)
    - No. 401. Texas (republic). Congress (Fourth). House. Committee of Finance, 1946 (Box 62, Folder 439)
    - No. 402-422, 1932-46 (Box 62, Folder 440)
    - No. 425. Texas (republic). Supreme Court. Rules of, 1939 (Box 62, Folder 441)
    - No. 427-469, 1927-49 (Box 62, Folder 442)
    - No. 470-488, 1927-46 (Box 62, Folder 443)
    - No. 491-549, 1927-80 (Box 63, Folder 444)
    - No. 554-596, 1927-46 (Box 63, Folder 445)
    - No. 602-638, 1927-46 (Box 63, Folder 446)
    - No. 639. Texas (republic). Convention, 1845. Standing Rules, 1939, 1946, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 447)
    - No. 645-663, 1927-46 (Box 63, Folder 448)
    - No. 665. Texas (state). Constitution, 1845, 1938-39, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 449)
    - No. 679. Texas (province). Gobernador, 1817-1822 (Antonio Martinez), 1952 (Box 63, Folder 450)
    - No. 680. Gaceta del Gobierno de México, 1957 (Box 63, Folder 451)
    - No. 681. [Cordéro y Bustamate, Manuel Antonio] Pretensions de los Anglo- Americanos, 1942, 1951, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 452)
    - No. 682-685A, 1939-45, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 453)
    - No. 687. Gómez, Farías, José María Valentín, 1940 (Box 63, Folder 454)
    - No. 689. Mexico (regency). Laws. (January 3, 1822) [Decree of the Soberana Junta], 1940 (Box 63, Folder 455)
    - No. 692. [Texas Association] Memorial que Varios Ciudadanos, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 456)
    - No. 695. Mexico (empire). Laws. (February. 25, 1823) [Decree of the Congreso constituyente], 1940-43 (Box 63, Folder 457)
    - No. 698. Mexico (provisional government). Primero Congreso Constituyene. Laws. (September 30, 1823), 1938, 1940, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 458)
    - No. 699. Provincias Internas de Oriente. Gefe Superior Politico y Comandante General, 1938-52, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 459)
    - No. 705. Mexico (republic). Laws. (October 17, 1825) [Decree of the Congreso General], 1940-55 (Box 63, Folder 460)
    - No. 708-708A, 1927-55 (Box 63, Folder 461)
    - No. 711. Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state). Laws. (November 21, 1826) [Decrees of the Congreso constituyente], 1941, 1951, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 462)
    - No. 714-720, 1939-40, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 463)
    - No. 722. Mexico (republic). Laws. (February 23, 1827), 1938, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 464)
    - No. 723. Noticia Estraordinaria, 1952 (Box 63, Folder 465)
    - No. 727. Coahuila and Texas (Mexican State). Laws. (March 24, 1825)...Ley de Colonizacion (Box 63, Folder 466)
    - No. 730-750, 1938-52, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 467)
    - No. 751. Coahuila and Texas (Mexican state)...Instrucciones á que debe arreglarse, 1940, 1950, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 468)
    - No. 753-776, 1931-52, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 469)
    - No. 781. Mexico (republic). Comision de Limites, 1941 (Box 63, Folder 470)
    - No. 782-795, 1939-49, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 471)
    - No. 795A. Tamaulipas (Mexican state). Laws. (November 13, 1833) [Decree no. 42 of Congreso constitucional], n.d. (Box 63, Folder 472)
    - No. 796-847, 1927-52 (Box 63, Folder 473)
    - No. 848. Alcerreca, Agustin. Manifesto que Publica el Coronel Graduado, 1941 (Box 64, Folder 474)
    - No. 849. Andrade, Juan José de, 1927, 1938 (Box 64, Folder 475)
    - No. 852-898, 1927-52, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 476)
    - No. 903 and note. La Opinión, San Luis Potosí. (June 22, 1836) and Diario of June 15, 1836, 1933, 1952, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 477)
    - No. 904. Por Extraordinario Llegado del Alamo, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 478)
    - No. 906. Se Nos ha Entregado, 1941 (Box 64, Folder 479)
    - No. 906A. Se Nos ha Entregado. Segunda Parte, 1941 (Box 64, Folder 480)
    - No. 909-918, 1927-52 (Box 64, Folder 481)
    - No. 919. Diario del Gobierno de la Republica Mexicana, 1947, 1957 (Box 64, Folder 482)
    - No. 920-933, 1927-40, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 483)
    - No. 934. Viesca, Augustin, 1957 (Box 64, Folder 484)
    - No. 935A. Vindication de los Crimenes Que Gratuitamente, 1939, 1940 (Box 64, Folder 485)
    - No. 936. Filisola, Vicente. Analisis del diario militar del General D. José Urréa, 1929, 1941 (Box 64, Folder 486-88)
    - No. 937-956, 1937-52 (Box 64, Folder 489)
    - No. 962. Chihuahua (Mexican state). Gobernador, 1840-1842 (Francisco Garcíca Conde), 1952 (Box 64, Folder 490)
    - No. 963-979, 1927-52 (Box 64, Folder 491)
    - No. 987-1000, 1927, 1952, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 492)
    - No. 1001. Mexico (republic). Ejército. Estado Mayor. Coleccion de Itinerarios (Box 64, Folder 493)
    - No. 1002. Mexico (republic). Ejército. Estada Mayor. Reglamento del Estado Mayor, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 494)
    - No. 1003A-1012, 1937, 1952, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 495)
    - No. 1013. Mexico (republic). Congreso. Cámara de Diputados. Comision Especial de Tejas, 1940 (Box 65, Folder 496)
    - No. 1016. Mexico (republic). Congreso. Senado. Discusion del Dicatamen de la Mayoria, 1940 (Box 65, Folder 497)
    - No. 1017. Mexico (republic). Congreso. Senado. Comisiones Unidas de puntos Constitucionales, 1940 (Box 65, Folder 498)
    - No. 1018. Mexico (republic). Congreso. Senado. Comisiones Unidas de Relaciones y Guerra, 1940 (Box 65, Folder 499)
    - No. 1021. Mexico (republic). Laws (June 4, 1845), 1937-38 (Box 65, Folder 500)
    - No. 1022. O Se Hace la Guerra de Tejas, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 501)
    - No. 1025-1026, 1939 (Box 65, Folder 502)
    - No. 1056. Keene, Richard Raynal, 1957 (Box 65, Folder 503)
    - No. 1082-1114, 1932-46 (Box 65, Folder 504)
    - No. 1121. Dominquez Grant, 1942 (Box 65, Folder 505)
    - No. 1123. Galveston Bay and Texas Land Company (Box 65, Folder 506)
    - No. 1129. Communication Forwarded from San Felipe, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 507)
    - No. 1140C. Sealsfield, Charles, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 508)
    - No. 1141. Texas (proposed Mexican state). Constitution, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 509)
    - No. 1162. Egerton, William H., n.d. (Box 65, Folder 510)
    - No. 1171B. Meyrick, Edwin, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 511)
    - No. 1182. [Bryan, William, and others] A Vindication of the Conduct, 1957 (Box 65, Folder 512)
    - No. 1184. Chambers, Thomas Jefferson, and others, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 513)
    - No. 1205-1236, 1938-39 (Box 65, Folder 514)
    - No. 1237. Texas (republic). [Contract containing terms of compromise...loan], 1947, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 515)
    - No. 1238-1424 (note), 1937-42, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 516)
    - No. 1444 (note) Arkansas Grant, 1958 (Box 65, Folder 517)
    - No. 1461. Texan Emigration and Land Company, London, 1941 (Box 65, Folder 518)
    - No. 1480-1576, 1938-47 (Box 66, Folder 519)
    - No. 1596. Mercer, Charles F., 1941 (Box 66, Folder 520)